Guide to the George P. Garrett Papers, 1929-2008 (bulk 1960-2000)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Material Series, 1970-1996 and undated
  - Lectures, Readings, and Presentations by Other Authors
    - Epps, Garrett, 1977, (2 tapes) (Box AV 13)
    - Freeman, Ann, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Fulton, Alice, 1986, Dec. 2, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Gaitskill, Mary, 1994, Feb. 20, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Gaitskill, Mary: Poetry panel, 1994, March 12, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Galvin, Brendan at Williams Corner Bookstore, 1991, Oct. 24, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Galvin, Brendan at University of Virginia, 1991, Oct. 24, (2 tapes) (Box AV 13)
    - Galvin at Folger Library, 1991, Oct. 28, (3 tapes) (Box AV 13)
    - Galvin at Roger Williams, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Gehman, Megan and Steinke, Darcey, 1987, March 3, (2 tapes) (Box AV 13)
    - Giardina, Denise and Chute, Carolyn, 1985, March 7, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Giardina, Denise: reading, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Hagy, Alyson, 1986, April 10, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Hankla, Cathryn, 1990, Feb. 11, (2 tapes) (Box AV 13)
    - Hankla, Cathy: reading, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Kiely, Ben, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Kinnell, Galway, 1987, July 14, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Lefkowicz, Peter and Megan Gehman, 1992, Nov. 18, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Levitas, Mike at University of Virginia, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Lit. Festival, 1991, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Matthiessen, Peter, 1991, April 16, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - McCorkle, Jill, 1991, April 5, (2 tapes) (Box AV 13)
    - Merwin, W.S., 1990, Jan. 22, (2 tapes) (Box AV 13)
    - Merwin, W.S. #1, 1991, Nov. 12, (2 tapes) (Box AV 13)
    - Merwin, 1991, Nov. 14, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Mewshaw, Mike, 1991, April 28, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Mueller, Craig and Michael Parker, 1991, Nov. 10, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - "Novelists as Critics" Panel, 1989, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Poster, Carol, 1990, April 21, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Rosengarten, Theodore, 1987, July 15, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Robison, Mary and Alan Cheuse, 1987, July 24, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Salter, James, 1991, Feb. 19, (2 tapes) (Box AV 13)
    - Settle, Mary Lee, 1992, March 12, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Settle, Mary Lee, 1993, Oct. 12, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Shepard, Jim and Russell Banks, 1987, July 15, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Slavitt, David at CWRU, 1986, Oct. 8, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Slavitt, David, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Taylor, Henry and Carolyn Kizer, 1986, Dec., (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Taylor, Henry, 1991, March 23, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Taylor and Fred Chappell, 1992, March 7, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Taylor, 1993, Feb. 21, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Thon, Melanie Rae, 1992, Dec. 2, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Tilghman, Christopher, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Vaughn, Betsy and Henry Taylor, 1994, March 12, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Vilmere, Daniel and Emily Ellison, 1987, July 17, (2 tapes) (Box AV 13)
    - Whitehead, James and Ellen Douglas, 1992, March 6, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Wilbur, Richard, 1987, July 21, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Wilbur, Richard at Bennington, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
    - Wier, Allen at University of Virginia, 1988, April 24, (1 tape) (Box AV 13)
  - Garrett's Classes, Readings, Speeches, Workshops, and Lectures
    - Garrett, 1981, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at NY Public Library, 1985, June 24, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at 2nd Street Gallery, 1985, Oct. 6, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at South Atlantic Modern Language Association, 1985, Nov. 1, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Rhode Island School of Design, 1986, Sept. 10, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at University of Massachusetts, 1987, Feb. 19, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Harvard, 1987, July 28, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Poetry Society of Va., 1987, Sept. 19, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: seminar at University of Tenn., 1987, Oct. 15, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at The Gallery, 1987, Dec., (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: interview, 1987, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: TV lectures, 1988, Feb. 14, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "The Fiction of Mary Lee Settle", 1988, April 20, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "Uncles and Others", 1988, April 21, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Fortnightly Club, 1988, May 3, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Ole Miss, 1988, Aug. 5, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "New Letters on the Air", 1988, Nov. 11, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Sewanee, 1989, Jan. 23, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at NVCC, 1989, Feb. 21, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Ginter Park Women's Club, 1989, March 15, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at George Mason University, 1989, March 27, (4 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Goucher College, 1989, April 17, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "Under Two Flags", 1989, April 21, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at The Gallery, 1989, April 30, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Western Carolina University, 1989, Oct. 23, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Coker College, 1990, Feb. 7, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: reading and class, 1990, May 12, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: talk to Friends of Orange County Library, 1990, May 15, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Orlando Library, 1990, May 15, and at Washington and Lee, 1990, May 28, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: talk to Writers' Club, 1990, May 30, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Washington and Lee and at Writers' Club, 1990, May, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: fiction class, 1990, May, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: talk to Young Writers Program, 1990, July 19, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Chapters Bookstore, 1990, Sept. 17, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Ft. Lauderdale Library, 1990, Oct. 2, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Roger Williams University, 1990, Oct. 5, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Hollins College, 1990, Oct. 9, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: reading at Southern Seminary, 1990, Oct. 11, (6 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - George Garrett Conversation, 1990, Oct. 25, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Virginia Military Institute, 1990, Dec. 4, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Pen/Malamud Awards, 1990, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Farmington, 1991, Jan. 10, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at University of North Carolina - Greensboro, 1991, Feb. 5, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Hillsdale College, 1991, Feb. 14, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Jefferson Society, 1991, March 2, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: reading to Faculty Wives' Club, 1991, April 1, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Hampden-Sydney, 1991, April 9, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: reading to Friends of Richmond Library, 1991, April 20, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: talk about "Bonfire of the Vanities," 1991, May 1, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Fla. Historical Society, 1991, May 10, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at University of Cincinnati, 1991, spring, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: reading to Friends of Handley Library, 1991, Sept. 11, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Reynolda House, 1991, Oct. 3, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at University of South Carolina, 1991, Oct. 30, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Christopher Newport College, 1991, Nov. 6, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: Phi Beta Kappa talk, 1991, Nov. 20, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - "George Garrett at Large," Jacksonville, Fla., 1991, Nov. 23, (3 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Emory University, 1992, Feb. 18, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: reading at Brentanos, 1992, July 21, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Commonwealth Center, 1992, Sept. 23, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at F.Scott Fitzgerald Conference, 1992, Sept. 25, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Sewanee, 1992, Sept. 30, and at Randolph Macon University, 1992, Nov. 8, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: speech at Sewanee Review banquet, 1992, Nov. 7, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at South Atlantic Modern Language Association, 1992, Nov. 13, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at American Association of University Women, 1992, Nov. 21, and at 2nd Street Gallery, 1992, Dec. 6, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: reading at 2nd Street Gallery, 1992, Dec. 6, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: class, 1993, April 29, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "That's What I Like (About the South)" reading, 1993, May 27, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Tucker Society, 1993, Aug. 12, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Williams Corner Bookstore, 1993, Sept. 29, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Alabama Symposium, 1993, Oct. 7, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Wisconsin, 1993, Oct. 20, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: speaking to University of Virginia Alumni Associates, 1993, Dec. 8, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Virginia Military Institute, 1994, March 8, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Borders Bookstore, 1994, May 3, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: readings, undated, (4 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: talk to high school teachers, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "New Letters on the Air", undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: talk and reading, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: poetry reading, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Aspen and Bennington, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Fla. International University and Ft. Lauderdale Library, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Reynolda House, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at CCVC, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: reading at Goddard, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "Under Two Flags," undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Sewanee and Vanderbilt, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Sewanee and Vanderbilt, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Stonecoast and Johnson State College, undated, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Michigan State, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - George Garrett, undated, (5 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Aspen, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at George Mason University, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at American University, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: interview, undated, (2 tapes) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: lecture, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Washington and Lee, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Stonecoast (inc.), undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: reading, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "Part 2," undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at UNH and Wesleyan, undated 91 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "Entered from the Sun", undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Tappa Hanock, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: talk at Weber State University, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: PhD. trip to Princeton, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett at Dana Hall, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: reading at American Audio Library, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "Genius Baby," undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
    - Garrett: "Poison Pen," undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 14)
  - Roundtables and Panels
    - Wesleyan Staff reading, 1987, June-July, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Taylor, Henry and Garrett, 1988, July 20, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Garrett and others at Museum of American History, 1989, June 4, (4 tapes) (Box AV 15)
    - Weekend Edition: Stanberg and Garrett, 1989, June 11, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Weekend Edition: "Wedding Cake Stories," 1989, June 11-July 23, (2 tapes) (Box AV 15)
    - Book and Author Dinner: Friends of the Knox County Library, 1989, Oct. 19, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Poets' Corner, 1989, Oct. 22, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Knoxville Book and Author Dinner, 1989, fall, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Writers Talking, 1990, Feb. 11, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Miami Book Fair, 1990, Nov. 17, (2 tapes) (Box AV 15)
    - "The Writing Life," 1991, Feb. 17, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - "Uneasy Muses," 1991, June 8, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Pen/Faulkner Awards Gala, 1991, Oct. 7, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Pen/Faulkner Awards Gala at Fogler Library, 1991, Nov. 7, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Morgan, Robert and Garrett at Writers' Network, 1991, Nov. 16, (3 tapes) (Box AV 15)
    - "Sources and Resources," 1991, Nov. 23, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Class: 1991, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - McElroy, Colleen and Garrett, 1992, March 6, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Humphreys, Josephine and Garrett, 1992, April 24, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Staff reading, 1992, July 1, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Reading for homeless at UVa, 1992, Sept. 22, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Dove, Rita and Garrett: excerpt from reading for homeless, 1992, Sept. 22, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Jefferson Scholars and AAUW, 1992, Nov. 2, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Chapters Bookstore, 1993, May 27, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Blair, Sydney and Garrett, 1993, Oct. 27, (2 tapes) (Box AV 15)
    - Staff reading, 1993, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - "Book Reviewing in America," undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Chappell, Fred and Garrett, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Garrett/Democrats, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - "Enchanted Ground," undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Huddle, David and Garrett, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Taylor, Henry and Garrett, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Misc. micro-cassettes, (23 tapes) (Box AV 15)
    - "Perspiration and Inspiration: The Craft and Vision of Writing," 1992, (12 tapes) (Box AV 15)
    - Book galley: "Entered from the Sun," 1990, Oct. 31, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - "The Modern American Novel" and "Literature of WWII," undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Garrett at Hillsdale College, undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Garrett: reading at WVCC, 1989, Feb. 21, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Panel discussion on creative writing programs at Hollins, 1986, Fall, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Garrett at CVCC, 1990, April 5, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - Prospectus for "Eminent Scholar/Teacher Series," undated, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - "Author-to-Author: The Fiction of Mary Lee Settle," 1990, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - "Author-to-Author: First Novelists," 1990, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - "Author-to-Author; Contemporary Short Story Writers," 1990, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
    - "Author-to Author: Contemporary Poets," 1990, (1 tape) (Box AV 15)
- Miscellaneous Papers Series, circa 1960-1996 and undated
  Chiefly comprised of printed material, clippings, bills and financial papers, schedules, notes, and itineraries.
  - Miscellaneous papers, (19 folders) (Box M 1)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (12 folders) (Box M 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (22 folders) (Box M 3)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (13 folders) (Box M 4)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (22 folders) (Box M 5)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (17 folders) (Box M 6)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (13 folders) (Box M 7)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (16 folders) (Box M 8)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (17 folders) (Box M 9)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (37 folders) (Box M 10)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (34 folders) (Box M 11)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (18 folders) (Box M 12)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (7 folders) (Box M 13)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (16 folders) (Box M 14)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (11 folders) (Box M 15)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (14 folders) (Box M 16)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (20 folders) (Box M 17)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (17 folders) (Box M 18)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (12 folders) (Box M 19)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (14 folders) (Box M 20)
- Accession #1998-0356
  This accession of the George Garrett Papers documents the life, career, and writing of the author and educator. The collection spans 1980 to 1998, chiefly 1995-1997, and consists of correspondence, writings (manuscripts, proofs, and drafts), clippings, audiotapes of various authors, including Garrett reading their works, and manuscripts from other authors submitted to Garrett for review and comment. This addition to the existing collection has received minimal processing and is open for research.
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    The personal and professional correspondence received by George Garrett between 1995 and 1998, chiefly 1996-1997, documents Garrett's career, professional relationships, and personal relationships with other writers and his students.
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, (17 folders) (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, (16 folders) (Box 2)
    - Frederick Busch, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - George Core / Sewanee Review, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - David Havrid, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Jan G. Hensley, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - LSU Press, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Hilary Masters, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Philip May, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - SMU, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Elizabeth Spencer, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Tom Whalen, (1 folder) (Box 2)
  - Writings (Box 3)
    The Writings Series includes the page proofs, typescripts, and handwritten manuscript pages of Garrett's recent poetry, non-fiction, and novels. Included in this series are several versions of Garrett's novel The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You, as well as his longer non-fiction pieces, Living with Elizabethans, Doing the Literary Thing, and Here and Now. The titles for the manuscript fragments and handwritten drafts were taken from the storage envelopes used by Garrett or are approximated from the text.
    - "Picking and Choosing", (1 folder) (Box 3)
      Page Proofs
    - The King of Babylon, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Doing the Literary Thing, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Then and There, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Living with Elizabethans, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, (8 folders) (Box 3)
      Typescripts of some of Garrett's shorter pieces, reviews, poetry and unidentified manuscript pages.
    - The King of Babylon, (3 folders) (Box 4)
      Typescript - "1st Draft"
    - The King of Babylon, (3 folders) (Box 4)
      Typescript - "Revised 8/28/95"
    - The King of Babylon, (2 folders) (Box 4)
      Typescript - "Original Revised 8/25/95"
    - The King of Babylon, (3 folders) (Box 4)
      Typescript - "2nd Version"
    - Here and Now, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Bad Man Blues, (1 folder) (Box 4)
      Page Proofs, 1998
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "It Hums, It Sings, It Dance", (1 folder) (Box 5)
      Handwritten draft
    - "The Pornagraphies", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "Alabama: A Perfect Stranger" and "Anecdotes", (1 folder) (Box 5)
      Handwritten draft and typescript
    - "Three Occasional Pieces", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "The Long Roll", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "Babylon", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "Hanging From the Trestle While the Train Goes By", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "Babylon - Popular Culture", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous Poems, (1 folder) (Box 5)
      Typescripts - "New Poems"
    - "Bad Man Blues", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "Part III - Essays", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "Heroes", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "Whatever Became of the King of Babylon?", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "Babylon: The Secret Book of Penrose Weatherby", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - Letter to the Fellowship of Southern Writers, (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "Wendell Berry Introduction", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts and Handwritten Drafts, (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    The Miscellaneous Series includes the manuscripts written by others submitted to Garrett for review and comment, conference materials, awards, and paperwork relating to Garrett's writing seminars and other classes.
  - Writings (Box 6)
    - "Days of Our Lives", (2 folders) (Box 6)
      Typescript
    - Miscellaneous Drafts and Notes, (8 folders) (Box 6)
    - Review of Playing With Fire (Box 6)
    - The Days of Our Lives Lie in Fragments, (2 folders) (Box 6)
      Page proofs
    - "Perfect Strangers", (1 folder) (Box 6)
      Handwritten manuscript
    - Review - "The Old Oxymoronic Itch...", (1 folder) (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Diary, 1985 (Box 6)
    - "William Goyen: The Terrible Embrace of Art" (Box 6)
      Texas Review, Page Proofs
    - Royalty Statements (Box 6)
    - Name Tags and Conference Materials (Box 6)
    - Farewell, I'm Bound to Leave You, by Fred Chappell, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - The Madhouse Nudes, by Robert Schultz, 1996, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - Hero, by Robert Dillen, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - "Poetry Anthology", (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - Extreme Justice, by Vincent S. Green, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - Swimming in the Congo, by Margaret Meyers, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - Black Transit, by Tom Alderson, (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - Señora Honeycomb, by Margaret Sayer Penden, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - Circling, by Paul Ruffin, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - Just Here, Just Now, by R.H.W. Dillard, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - The Leap, by Sebastian Rotella, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Hotel Malabar, by Brendan Galvin, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - Daytime and Starlight, by James Appelwhite, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - Jack Horner in Love and War, by R.V. Cassill, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - The White Rooster and Other Stories, by Robert Bausch, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - The Tent of Orange Mist, by Paul West, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Clippings, (13 folders) (Box 8)
    The Clippings Series includes newspaper and magazine clippings, flyers for reading and other events, publisher catalogs, and other promotional materials.
  - Audio Cassettes (Box 9)
    Tapes of readings and speeches by George Garrett and others, 1980-1996, and undated The titles for the tapes were established by Garrett. An alphabetical (by reader) list of tapes follows and is enclosed with the cassettes.
    - Unidentified
      - "Intro to Nims" (Box 9)
      - Enchanted Ground, 1980 (Box 9)
      - Fellowship of Southern Writers, Uva, 1996 (Box 9)
      - Fiction Reading, Johns Hopkins, 1996 (Box 9)
      - New Letters on the Air (Box 9)
    - Award
      - Frederick Wiseman Documentary, VA Festival of American Film, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Battestin, Martin
      - Interview (Box 9)
    - Battestin, Martin and Ruthe
      - Talks, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Bausch, Garrett, Bloom
      - Wesleyan/Presbyterian Readings (Box 9)
    - Bausch, Richard and Robert
      - Reading, UVA, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Bausch, Richard and George Garrett
      - Reading, Bennington, VT, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Berry, Wendell and Henry Taylor
      - Aiken-Taylor Awards, Sewanee, TN (Box 9)
    - Blair, Casey, Eisenberg, Garrett, Settle
      - "Our Place," Virgina Festival of the Book, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Blair, Sydney, Debra Nystrom
      - Reading, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Brown, Rita Mae; George Garrett; Ann Beattie; Eudora Welty
      - Literacy Reading, UVA, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Buechner, Frederick (2 cassettes)
      - Reading, UVA (Box 9)
      - Reading from Son of Laughter, UVA (Box 9)
    - Chandler, Marilyn; George Garrett; Diane Johnson
      - Varieties of Literary Biography (Box 9)
    - Chappell, Fred; George Garrett ( Wilma Dykeman, moderator)
      - Book & Author Dinner, Knoxville, TN, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Cheuse, Alan
      - Reading (Box 9)
    - Chute, Caroline; Maggie Anderson
      - Hollins Literary Festival (Box 9)
    - Ciardi, John
      - "Speaking of Words," National Public Radio (Box 9)
    - Cooley, Nicole; Tom Whalen; George Garrett
      - Reading, Wurzburg, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Crews, Harry (2 cassettes)